♪The wind once paused by the rain streaked window♪
♪توقفت الرياح ذات مرة عند النافذة التي لطختها قطرات المطر♪
♪Sketching you in gentle strokes♪
♪أرسمك بخطوط رقيقة♪
♪From the old town, cooking smoke curled upward♪
♪من البلدة القديمة، تصاعد دخان الطهي♪
♪Smoothing the tide of my restless thoughts♪
♪تهدئة موجة أفكاري المضطربة♪
=A Vow in the Dark=
=عهد في الظلام=
=Episode 24=
=الحلقة 24=
- It's the Dragon Ancestor! - The Dragon Ancestor!
- إنه سلف التنين! - سلف التنين!
The Dragon Ancestor has appeared!
لقد ظهر سلف التنين!
Yes.
نعم.
The Dragon Ancestor.
سلف التنين.
The Dragon Ancestor is here.
سلف التنين هنا.
He's come to save us!
لقد جاء لينقذنا!
He's come to mend the Artifact!
لقد جاء لإصلاح القطعة الأثرية!
That's sunlight.
هذا ضوء الشمس.
- Real sunlight! - Wonderful!
- ضوء الشمس الحقيقي! - رائع!
Sunlight at last!
أخيراً أشرقت الشمس!
Sunlight!
ضوء الشمس!
Sunlight is bathing both realms.
ضوء الشمس يغمر كلا العالمين.
We'll never have to fight over it again.
لن نضطر أبدًا إلى الشجار بشأنه مرة أخرى.
Hurray!
يا هلا!
Long live the Dragon Ancestor!
عاش سلف التنين!
Thank you, Dragon Ancestor!
شكراً لك يا جد التنين!
Hurray!
يا هلا!
Does it hurt?
هل يؤلمك؟
From this day on,
ابتداءً من هذا اليوم،
immortals and demons
الخالدون والشياطين
shall know no more war.
لن يعرفوا الحرب بعد الآن.
You and I
أنت وأنا
will wander the Three Realms,
سيتجول في العوالم الثلاثة،
never leaving each other's side.
لا يفترقان أبداً.
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
But the fish bone inside me
لكن عظمة السمكة بداخلي
will keep draining your Demonic Ether.
سيستمر في استنزاف الأثير الشيطاني الخاص بك.
As long as I can stay with you,
طالما أستطيع البقاء معك،
nothing else matters.
لا شىئ اخر يهم.
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدًا،
we'll be the most ordinary couple
سنكون أكثر زوجين عاديين
in Hunling City.
في مدينة هانلينغ.
I can gladly lose
يمكنني أن أخسر بكل سرور
the Demonic Ether.
الأثير الشيطاني.
This pouch.
هذه الحقيبة.
(May)
(يمكن)
(the two realms)
(العالمان)
(know eternal peace.)
(اعرف السلام الأبدي.)
You didn't toss it up?
ألم تقم برميها؟
How could I
كيف لي أن أفعل ذلك؟
hand your wish to Feng Tian?
هل تود أن تسلم أمنيتك إلى فنغ تيان؟
I'll make it come true
سأجعل ذلك حقيقة
for you.
لك.
Ji Li,
جي لي,
we're on the same side now.
نحن الآن في نفس الجانب.
Will you
سوف تفعل
marry me?
تزوجيني؟
Now, order is restored,
الآن، عاد النظام.
and everything is back to normal.
وعاد كل شيء إلى طبيعته.
Hong Zhua,
هونغ تشو,
where is Jin Li's body?
أين جثة جين لي؟
It must not fall
يجب ألا يسقط
into demon hands.
في أيدي الشياطين.
Your Grace,
صاحب السمو،
the Three Realms are at peace,
الممالك الثلاث تعيش في سلام،
so Jin Li's body need not appear.
لذا فليس من الضروري ظهور جثة جين لي.
The great war
الحرب العظمى
brought years of disaster to Hunling City;
جلبت سنوات من الكوارث لمدينة هانلينغ؛
our merit was long spent.
لقد استُنفدت جهودنا منذ زمن طويل.
Jie Chuan ended the strife
أنهى جي تشوان الصراع
and repaired the Artifact.
وقام بإصلاح القطعة الأثرية.
Even without Demonic Ether,
حتى بدون الأثير الشيطاني،
even blind,
حتى الأعمى،
he still holds the hearts of all.
لا يزال يحتل مكانة في قلوب الجميع.
Nonsense!
هراء!
You once promoted me,
لقد قمت بترقيتي ذات مرة،
but our ways now diverge.
لكن طرقنا الآن تختلف.
I now have my own path.
الآن لدي طريقي الخاص.
Jin Li's body
جثة جين لي
shall guard the Three Realms forever.
سيحرسون العوالم الثلاثة إلى الأبد.
I request to be struck
أطلب أن أُضرب
from the immortal rolls.
من سجلات الخالدين.
I kept watch through myriad nights.
ظللت أراقب طوال ليالٍ لا تُحصى.
Does that count for less than Jie Chuan's single rescue?
هل يُعتبر ذلك أقل من عملية الإنقاذ الوحيدة التي قام بها جي تشوان؟
(Hong Residence)
(مقر إقامة هونغ)
I'm no longer the Demon Sovereign.
لم أعد سيد الشياطين.
Do you think
هل تعتقد
anyone will come to our wedding feast?
هل سيحضر أحد حفل زفافنا؟
With your terrible popularity?
مع شعبيتك المتدنية؟
Of course not.
بالطبع لا.
I'm different.
أنا مختلف.
Everyone immortal
الجميع خالدون
(Invitation) will surely come
ستأتي الدعوة بالتأكيد
and eat everything you prepare.
وتناول كل ما تعده.
Ji Li! Ji Li!
جي لي! جي لي!
Ying Ge!
يينغ جي!
Ying Ge's here!
يينغ غي هنا!
Ying Ge, are you here for our wedding?
يينغ غي، هل أنتِ هنا لحضور حفل زفافنا؟
Feng Tian is about
فنغ تيان يدور حول
to destroy the world and rebuild it.
لتدمير العالم وإعادة بنائه.
Isn't he already ruler of both realms?
أليس هو بالفعل حاكم المملكتين؟
Why bother?
لماذا كل هذا العناء؟
Ruler?
حاكم؟
But no one acknowledges him.
لكن لا أحد يعترف به.
After Jie Chuan repaired the Artifact,
بعد أن قام جي تشوان بإصلاح القطعة الأثرية،
he became the one the Three Realms accept.
أصبح هو الشخص الذي تقبله العوالم الثلاثة.
Deprived of popular support,
محروم من الدعم الشعبي،
Feng Tian fled to Wasteland
فرّ فنغ تيان إلى أرض قاحلة
and found Devourer's spell
ووجد تعويذة المُلتهم
that feeds on emotions and desires.
التي تتغذى على العواطف والرغبات.
He plans to turn all who defy him
يخطط لتحويل كل من يتحداه.
into puppets.
إلى دمى.
His power has soared.
لقد ازدادت قوته بشكل كبير.
He's now indestructible.
أصبح الآن لا يُقهر.
He swears
يقسم
to wipe out Jie Chuan.
للقضاء على جي تشوان.
The Three Realms will face chaos once more.
ستواجه العوالم الثلاثة الفوضى مرة أخرى.
Your Grace,
صاحب السمو،
you still act against everyone in the end.
في النهاية، ستظل تتصرف ضد الجميع .
For whose sake did we devise
من أجل من ابتكرنا
the demon-slaying plan?
خطة قتل الشياطين؟
You became a spy,
لقد أصبحت جاسوساً،
fell in love with Jie Chuan,
وقعت في حب جي تشوان،
yet in the end obeyed Feng Tian's command,
ومع ذلك، فقد أطاع في النهاية أمر فنغ تيان.
betrayed Jie Chuan,
خيانة جي تشوان
and died by his hand.
ومات على يده.
But none of us foresaw
لكن لم يتوقع أحد منا ذلك
that Jie Chuan would trade all his memories
أن جي تشوان سيضحي بكل ذكرياته
for a single fish bone,
من أجل عظمة سمكة واحدة،
sealing it inside Ji Li.
إحكام إغلاقها داخل جي لي.
Ji Li,
جي لي,
innocent and lively,
بريء وحيوي،
never knew
لم أكن أعرف
she was already a piece on the board.
لقد كانت بالفعل قطعة على رقعة الشطرنج.
400 years have passed;
لقد مرت 400 سنة؛
they now love each other dearly,
إنهم الآن يحبون بعضهم البعض بشدة،
yet Feng Tian has become
لكن فنغ تيان أصبح
the one who'd destroy the world.
الشخص الذي سيدمر العالم.
If you were in their place,
لو كنت مكانهم،
what choice would you make?
ما هو الخيار الذي ستتخذه؟
I still remember our first meeting.
ما زلت أتذكر لقاءنا الأول.
You were punished for stealing my wine
لقد عوقبت لسرقة نبيذي
and then turned my life
ثم غيرت حياتي
upside down for 100 years.
مقلوبة رأساً على عقب لمدة 100 عام.
The most domineering immortal in my life.
أكثر الخالدين تسلطاً في حياتي.
But if I make
لكن إذا صنعت
this choice for you today,
هذا الخيار لك اليوم،
I'm afraid I won't find peace
أخشى أنني لن أجد السلام
even after death.
حتى بعد الموت.
Jin Li,
جين لي,
I once promised we'd share good wine.
لقد وعدت ذات مرة بأننا سنتشارك النبيذ الجيد.
I broke that promise.
لقد أخلفت ذلك الوعد.
Don't hold it against me.
لا تلومني على ذلك.
The world was thrown into chaos by this fish bone scheme.
لقد غرق العالم في الفوضى بسبب مخطط عظم السمكة هذا.
It's time
حان الوقت
for the two of us to end it.
لكي ننهي الأمر نحن الاثنين.
Master.
يتقن.
Please set the array for me.
أرجو منك تحديد المصفوفة لي.
If the Fish-Bone Array can kill Jie Chuan,
إذا كان بإمكان مصفوفة عظم السمكة قتل جي تشوان،
it can kill Feng Tian as well.
ويمكنه أن يقتل فينغ تيان أيضاً.
Ji Li,
جي لي,
the Fish-Bone Array is a self-destructive.
مصفوفة عظم السمكة هي مدمر ذاتيًا.
Once Feng Tian dies,
بمجرد وفاة فينغ تيان،
you will dissolve and perish, too.
ستتلاشى أنت أيضاً وتفنى.
Have you thought this through?
هل فكرت في هذا الأمر جيداً؟
Jie Chuan has done enough for me.
لقد قدم جي تشوان ما يكفي من أجلي.
Feng Tian wants to unmake the world.
يريد فنغ تيان تدمير العالم.
Right now, the only one who can stand
في الوقت الحالي، الشخص الوحيد القادر على الوقوف
before Jie Chuan is me.
قبل أن يكون جي تشوان أنا.
I've decided.
لقد قررت.
Please set the array.
يرجى تحديد المصفوفة.
Master.
يتقن.
You're my disciple.
أنت تلميذي.
How could I let you face it alone?
كيف لي أن أتركك تواجه الأمر وحدك؟
I have poured
لقد سكبتُ
all the power of Jin Li and me
كل قوة جين لي وأنا
into the fish bone.
في عظمة السمكة.
The ice spike can slay Feng Tian
بإمكان مسمار الجليد أن يقتل فينغ تيان
and still leave you alive.
ومع ذلك سيتركك على قيد الحياة.
Master!
يتقن!
May you and Jie Chuan
أتمنى لك وجي تشوان
grow old together in peace
سنكبر معاً في سلام
after this battle.
بعد هذه المعركة.
No!
لا!
Master!
يتقن!
Master...
يتقن...
Feng Tian!
فنغ تيان!
It's me.
هذا أنا.
Jie Chuan,
جي تشوان,
you're worthless now.
أنت الآن بلا قيمة.
Why do they still worship you as ruler?
لماذا ما زالوا يعبدونك كحاكم؟
I won't accept it!
لن أقبل بذلك!
So,
لذا،
you'd destroy the world?
هل ستدمر العالم؟
Hypocrite!
منافق!
If you don't shelter your people,
إذا لم توفر الحماية لشعبك،
they will turn against you.
سينقلبون عليك.
Even without me,
حتى بدون وجودي،
they'd find another worthy man
سيجدون رجلاً آخر جديراً.
to follow.
يتبع.
Nonsense!
هراء!
Once I kill you,
بمجرد أن أقتلك،
I become the only ruler!
سأصبح الحاكم الوحيد!
What a surprise.
يا لها من مفاجأة!
The mighty Demon Sovereign
سيد الشياطين الجبار
has been so weak.
كان ضعيفاً للغاية.
Jie Chuan,
جي تشوان,
you're useless now.
أنت عديم الفائدة الآن.
Feng Tian,
فنغ تيان,
you stand alone.
أنت تقف وحيداً.
Master and Jin Li gave their souls
قدّم السيد وجين لي روحيهما
to set things right.
لإصلاح الأمور.
Now,
الآن،
after such a long-term scheme,
بعد مثل هذه الخطة طويلة الأمد،
the blade meant to slay demons
النصل المصمم لقتل الشياطين
falls on you.
يقع عليك.
Ji Li.
جي لي.
Jie Chuan,
جي تشوان,
we met and fell in love.
التقينا ووقعنا في الحب.
Even if I die today,
حتى لو مت اليوم،
I won't regret it.
لن أندم على ذلك.
Just don't leave me behind.
لا تتركني وحدي.
Whatever you do, I agree.
مهما فعلت، فأنا أوافقك.
You revived Jin Li.
لقد قمت بإحياء جين لي.
Why aren't you dead?
لماذا لم تمت؟
I was once a weak immortal
كنتُ في يوم من الأيام خالداً ضعيفاً
and thought the war was far away.
وظن أن الحرب بعيدة.
Then I fell in love with Jie Chuan
ثم وقعت في حب جي تشوان
and learned
وتعلم
the distant war was right before me.
كانت الحرب البعيدة أمام عيني مباشرة.
Now,
الآن،
I step forward for all living things,
أتقدم من أجل جميع الكائنات الحية،
ready to give my life
مستعد للتضحية بحياتي
for righteousness,
من أجل البر،
to guard the future I believe in,
لحماية المستقبل الذي أؤمن به،
to guard Jie Chuan,
لحراسة جي تشوان،
to guard every soul I cherish.
لحماية كل روح أعتز بها.
Why would I lose?
لماذا سأخسر؟
Why?
لماذا؟
♪Iron hooves stall the flow of time♪
♪حوافر حديدية تعيق تدفق الزمن♪
♪Just to catch a glimpse of you♪
♪فقط لألقي نظرة خاطفة عليك♪
♪From this life on, no debts remain between us♪
♪من هذه الحياة فصاعدًا، لن تبقى بيننا أي ديون♪
You're a good demon.
أنت شيطان طيب.
♪If we cannot renew the bond of our past in this life♪
♪إذا لم نتمكن من تجديد روابط ماضينا في هذه الحياة♪
♪Let me remember your face forever♪
♪دعني أتذكر وجهك إلى الأبد♪
♪The mortal world is filled with partings and sorrow♪
♪العالم الفاني مليء بالفراق والحزن♪
May the two realms
لعل العالمين
know eternal peace.
أنعم بالسلام الأبدي.
♪If in the next life, spring winds long for rivers and seas♪
♪إذا كانت رياح الربيع في الحياة الأخرى تتوق إلى الأنهار والبحار♪
♪I'll hold you close when peach blossoms shine bright♪
سأضمك إليّ عندما تتألق أزهار الخوخ
♪Each strand of hair reminds me of our very first meeting♪
كل خصلة شعر تذكرني بلقائنا الأول
I'll do it.
سأفعل ذلك.
Did you burn yourself?
هل أحرقت نفسك؟
No.
لا.
(Hong Residence)
(مقر إقامة هونغ)
♪Thin wisps of smoke weave through the river♪
♪خيوط رقيقة من الدخان تتسلل عبر النهر♪
♪Melodies and wine fade, drunk beneath the sunset♪
تتلاشى الألحان والنبيذ، ونحن نُشرب تحت غروب الشمس.
♪Lonely light and sword shadow sway the falling leaves♪
♪ضوء وحيد وظل سيف يتمايلان مع الأوراق المتساقطة♪
♪Laughing at my recklessness in this life♪
أضحك على تهوّري في هذه الحياة
♪You come to me in every way♪
♪تأتون إليّ بكل الطرق♪
♪Filling my dreams with tangled love and hate♪
♪أملأ أحلامي بمزيج من الحب والكراهية♪
♪All my best years were for you♪
♪كل أجمل سنوات عمري كانت من أجلك♪
♪At the far edge of the world where lanterns fade♪
♪على الحافة البعيدة للعالم حيث تخبو الفوانيس♪
♪Through the mortal dust, time flows with its trials♪
♪عبر غبار الفناء، يتدفق الزمن بمحنه♪
♪Joys and sorrows ease grief♪
♪الأفراح والأحزان تخفف من وطأة الحزن♪
♪At dusk, petals fall as winter snow carries the starlight♪
♪عند الغسق، تتساقط البتلات بينما يحمل ثلج الشتاء ضوء النجوم♪
♪Across endless lifetimes, the ballad endures♪
♪عبر أجيال لا حصر لها، تبقى الأغنية خالدة♪